enhancetv.com.au 2015-04-28

# EnhanceTV - Privacy

|  | Stream Video   
---  
 | EnhanceTV Direct  
What's On  
  | TV Highlights  
 | TV Guide  
 | Email Guide  
Get a Copy  
 | Video Downloads  
[](http://www.enahncetv.com.au/images/HomePage/series_download_small.jpg) | Series Downloads   
Teach with TV  
 | Study Guides  
 | Feature Articles  
 | Teaching Topics   
Connect & Share  
 | RSS Feeds  
 | Podcasts  
Extras  
 | Taping Requests  
 | DVD Covers  
  
|  PRIVACY POLICY   
---  
  
|    
---  
**1\. General policy**  

EnhanceTV Pty Ltd of Level 1, 140 Myrtle Street, Chippendale, NSW 2008 (ABN 72 119 702 251) ( **EnhanceTV** ) understands the importance of privacy to the public, including users of the EnhanceTV website at www.enhancetv.com, the web-based streaming application EnhanceTV Direct located at http://direct.enhancetv.com.au and any other websites (each a **Website** , collectively the **Websites)** , products and services that EnhanceTV operates (each a **Service** , collectively the **Services** ).

EnhanceTV will deal with Personal Information in accordance with this policy (the **Privacy Policy** ) and as required by law, including the Australian Privacy Principles ( **APPs** ) (available at the website of the **[Office of the Australian Information Commissioner](http://oaic.gov.au/)** under the _Privacy Act 1988_ (Cth).  This Privacy Policy sets out how EnhanceTV collects, stores, maintains, discloses and protects the Personal Information that you provide to EnhanceTV from time to time. It also sets out your rights of access to the Personal Information that EnhanceTV holds about you.

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy  **Personal Information**  means information or an opinion (including information or an opinion forming part of a database), whether true or not, and whether recorded in a material form or not, about an individual whose identity is apparent, or can reasonably be ascertained, from the information or opinion. 

By providing EnhanceTV with Personal Information, you consent to the use and disclosures described in this policy. This Privacy Policy does not apply to other websites to which the Websites may be linked.  

**2\. Collection of your Personal Information**  

EnhanceTV collects Personal Information relating to content providers, educational and media industry professionals and participants and Website and other Service users as part of the normal course of its business.  

Generally, where possible, EnhanceTV will collect Personal Information directly from you or from persons you have authorised to provide information to us about you. Should you wish to remain completely anonymous, do not log into a Website as you will have identified yourself in doing so and do not provide us with any information that may identify you. Where possible, EnhanceTV we will allow you to use a pseudonym when contributing to our Websites. 

In general, the Personal Information that EnhanceTV collects includes (but is not limited to) names, contact details (including phone numbers and postal and email addresses), educational institutions, details of relevant memberships or associations and details of relevant licence schemes, financial information (including payment and billing information and credit card details). Such information may be collected in the process of Service enquiries, Service applications, Website user enquiries, Website user registrations, use of Websites, email correspondence, notes taken by EnhanceTV staff of telephone and face-to-face meetings and surveys undertaken by EnhanceTV or a third party on its behalf for the purposes of gathering user experience information in order to improve our Services and through your interactions with EnhanceTV which may include entering competitions and through social media.

Sometimes, EnhanceTV may also collect Personal Information such as contact information from a third party or a publicly available source, but only if the individual has consented to such collection or would reasonably expect us to collect their Personal Information in this way.  In limited circumstances, EnhanceTV may receive Personal Information about third parties from individuals who contact us and supply us with the Personal Information of others in the documents the individuals provide to us. 

EnhanceTV only collects Personal Information for purposes that are related to EnhanceTV’s business and only when it is necessary for or directly related to such purposes. EnhanceTV’s business includes (without limitation):  
  
  * Providing and administering the Services such as EnhanceTV Direct, including billing;
  * Curating an archive of screen content for use in education;
  * Providing information on the content available;
  * Making such content available for use in education via streaming through EnhanceTV Direct and via downloads through its online store located at http://www.enhancetv.com.au;
  * Offering options to access such content on multiple devices; and
  * Creating or curating resources that supplement such content such as study guides, lesson plans, closed captions, clip collections and features articles. 

**3\. Information logged and cookies**  

Apart from any Personal Information that you provide to EnhanceTV, servers used in EnhanceTV’s operations may gather information provided by your browser when you visit the Websites. This may include:  
  
  * The date and time of your visit;
  * The pages you access;
  * The content, including videos and documents, that you view or download;
  * Browser type;
  * Searches you perform on the Websites;
  * Your client’s public Internet Protocol (IP) address; and
  * If you have been referred to the Websites from another website, the address of the referring website.

EnhanceTV Websites may also use “cookie” technology to assist in identifying you and delivering content specific to your interests.  Cookies were originally designed to assist a website to distinguish a user as a prior user, manage the user’s experience and to recall any prior preferences of that user.  A cookie is a small string of text that a site sends to your browser. A cookie cannot retrieve any other data from your hard drive, pass on computer viruses or capture your email address. Cookies are used to enhance a user's visit. For example, cookies can securely store a user's ID and password, personalise home pages, identify previously visited parts of a site and keep track of selections in a “shopping cart”.  If you become a registered user of one of our Websites (with a designated ID and password) EnhanceTV may use cookies to provide you with personalised information that we feel, based on the preferences you have made when visiting the Website, might be of interest and value to you.

Further, EnhanceTV Websites may also incorporate an analytics system using a combination of cookies and activity logs to gather information regarding user activity on the Websites. This is collated into both aggregate results and records of individual users. For example, EnhanceTV Websites incorporate the Google Analytics system to gather statistics about how our Websites are accessed and used. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the Website will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers located outside of Australia, which may include the United States. No personally identifying information is collected. The use of Google Analytics by Google is subject to [the Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) and is not covered by our Privacy Policy. You can opt out of Google Analytics by using the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB) or set your browser to refuse or delete cookies from Google Analytics.

In relation to information logged and cookies referred to above, EnhanceTV gathers such information to monitor usage of our Websites and to understand the Websites’ use and relevance. This enables us to improve and enhance the Websites, to make the Websites more user-friendly and to make the Websites more relevant to users.

From time to time, EnhanceTV engages independent contractors to perform analytics and related services and in such cases will make all reasonable efforts to ensure that contracts with such independent contractors include an obligation to comply with Australian privacy laws or apply privacy standards that meet or exceed requirements of Australian law.

  Additionally, EnhanceTV may use also use suppliers who also set cookies on our Websites on our behalf in order to deliver the services that they are providing. For example, if EnhanceTV embeds photos and video content from third party content platforms on the Websites, those third parties may have set cookies relating to that content. If you then share that content, another third party cookie may be set by the service you have chosen to share content through. EnhanceTV does not control these cookies, and does not block cookies set by third parties in these ways.  
  
**4\. Use and disclosure**  

EnhanceTV will only use Personal Information for the purposes for which it was given to us, or for purposes which are directly related to one of our functions or activities.

EnhanceTV may use and disclose your Personal Information in order to provide Services to you and to improve the Services that it offers generally and may use your Personal Information to contact you for these purposes, including to inform you of upcoming events, television programs or other sites or publications which we reasonably believe may be of interest to you. 

EnhanceTV may also use and disclose your Personal Information to help it assess and survey the ways in which users use the Services. To the extent that it is reasonably practicable, this information will be de-identified so that you are not personally identifiable in the results of any such assessment or survey.

Any financial information such as credit card details that you provide will be used solely for the purpose for which you provide them, such as the payment for subscriptions services for example. EnhanceTV will not sell, share, rent or receive payment for licensing or disclosing your Personal Information.

Generally, EnhanceTV must get your consent before it discloses any of your Personal Information. You may give your consent expressly or it may be implied by your conduct. Depending on the Service you have requested or otherwise engaged with, your Personal Information may be disclosed to:  
  
  * External service providers who assist us in providing and administering the Services such as EnhanceTV Direct, competitions, events and promotions, including third party suppliers, contractors and data storage providers;
  * Specialist advisers who have been engaged to provide EnhanceTV with legal, administrative, financial, insurance, research, marketing or other services;
  * Third party research companies to conduct surveys about EnhanceTV’s Services to you. Participation in such surveys is optional;
  * Independent auditors engaged to audit EnhanceTV’ operational practices; and
  * Any other person authorised by you or specified by you.

There will, of course, be times when it will be necessary for EnhanceTV to disclose your Personal Information to third parties without your consent. For instance, where it is required or authorised to do so by law, law enforcement bodies or otherwise permitted by law under APP 6.  

**5\. International transfers**  

EnhanceTV may disclose your Personal Information to third parties located overseas, specifically in the United States and Luxembourg, who provide online survey and email management services to us. Otherwise, EnhanceTV will not usually disclose your Personal Information overseas, but if we do we will notify you at the time. For example, where a partner or sponsor of a competition run by EnhanceTV is located overseas, EnhanceTV may transfer Personal Information we collect from you to their location, the countries of which may vary.  If we do this, we will notify you of the location at the time you enter into the competition. Privacy laws in Australia guide our privacy practices. The privacy laws of other countries may not be as comprehensive or equivalent to those in Australia. By using the Services, you consent to the collection, international transfer, storage, and processing of your Personal Information as set forth in this Privacy Policy and any other privacy notice provided at the time the Personal Information is collected.   

**6\. Storage and Security of your Personal Information**  

EnhanceTV takes all reasonable steps to protect your Personal Information from loss, unauthorised access, modification, disclosure or other misuse. This includes: using electronic access restrictions for electronic files that contain Personal Information, securing paper files containing Personal Information and physical access restrictions to files containing Personal Information. All transactions that involve the provision of Personal Information for the ordering of videotapes are fully encrypted by our secure server. Where EnhanceTV stores your Personal Information with a third party data storage provider, we require them to keep it secure and only use or disclose it for the purpose for which it was provided.   

**7\. Accessing and Updating your Personal Information**  

Whenever possible, EnhanceTV will provide you with access to the Personal Information that EnhanceTV holds about you to ensure that is accurate, complete and up to date. If your Personal Information is not accurate, complete or up to date and you cannot access or update your Personal Information, please inform the EnhanceTV Privacy Officer using the Contact details set out below and EnhanceTV will take all reasonable steps to correct the information.  

**8\. Direct Marketing Communications and Opting out**  

EnhanceTV may, from time to time, send direct marketing communications to you about its activities and other material that it considers you would find useful.  If you do not wish to receive such direct marketing communications, you can **[contact EnhanceTV](https://www.enhancetv.com.au/shop/help.php?section=contactus&mode=update) **and EnhanceTV will endeavour to meet your request in a timely manner. 

EnhanceTV’s Services and communications with you may also contain specific methods to opt out of direct marketing material sent via the particular Service or communication. 

If you choose opt out of all direct marketing communications, please note that EnhanceTV may still contact you for other reasonable purposes, including information that EnhanceTV is legally required to send and information regarding the rights, benefits or obligations of users of Services.  

**9\. Contact details**  

If you require any further information or have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy or if you wish to access or correct your Personal Information or make a complaint about our handling of that information, please contact the EnhanceTV Privacy Officer as follows:  
  
Email: privacy@enhancetv.com.au  
Telephone: +61 2 9904 0009  
Facsimile: +61 2 9904 0498   
Postal Address: The Privacy Officer, EnhanceTV, PO Box 853, Broadway NSW 2007 Australia  

**10\. Complaints Handling Procedure**  

Any complaint about handling of Personal Information will be dealt with in accordance with the following EnhanceTV Privacy Complaints Handling Procedure: ****  

  * If you think that an act or practice of EnhanceTV has interfered with your privacy in relation to Personal Information you may make a complaint to EnhanceTV. 
  * The complaint must identify you and be in written form and addressed to the EnhanceTV Privacy Officer.
  * The EnhanceTV Privacy Officer will investigate your complaint and will endeavour to provide a response setting out EnhanceTV’s decision in writing within 30 days of receipt of your complaint.
  * If EnhanceTV is unable to satisfactorily resolve your concerns you can contact the **[Office of the Australian Information Commissioner](http://oaic.gov.au/)**. 

**11\. Changes to this Privacy Policy**  

EnhanceTV may amend this Privacy Policy by substituting amended terms and posting it on the Websites. Any such amendment will be effective upon notification to you by any means.  At a minimum, notice will be given by posting a notice on the Websites to the effect that the Privacy Policy has changed.  In any event, continued use of any Website following those amendments constitutes acceptance of the revised Privacy Policy in relation to the Services.
